ALBERTO GAONA

Location: Ramos Arizpe, Coahuila, México **Phone**: (011 52 1) 844-278-3346

Email: albertoo_3c@hotmail.com GitHub: betogaona7 LinkedIn: betogaona7 Portfolio: betogaona7

Engineering graduate passionate about deep learning with +1 year software engineering experience, eager to collaborate in the research and development of new AI technology based on insights, universal emotional motivators, that can improve people's lives by building and deploying artificial intelligence systems into a machine learning engineer position at Nexus Edge.

EDUCATION

Udacity
On line

Artificial Intelligence and Specializations Nanodegree Deep Learning Nanodegree Foundation

Digital Invaders Saltillo, Coahuila

Innovation and Technological Creativity 08/2016 – 12/2016

Universidad Autónoma de Coahuila Arteaga, Coahuila

Computer Systems Engineer Bachelor's Degree 08/2012 – 06/2017

SKILLS

Programming languages: Python, C++, Java, C# Cloud services: AWS-EC2 instances Version Control: Git

Frameworks: **TensorFlow**, **Keras** Operating systems: **Linux**, **Windows** Languages: **Spanish**, **English**

PROJECTS

DNN Speech Recognizer 03/2018

 Analyzed five different neural networks architectures using a small dataset of 2100+ audio samples to testing their performance for acoustic modeling.

• Outperformed the best model of the previous architecture research by building a deep neural network that achieved 19% less validation loss in only one-third of the time to convert audio sound waves into language text.

EN-FR translator 02/2018

- Evaluated four neural networks architectures commonly used for natural language processing using a small dataset of 227 English words to compare their performance for a translation task.
- Surpassed the four models of the previous research with an accuracy of 94% developing a deep recurrent neural network architecture that accepts English text as input and returns the French translation.

Facial Key-Points Detector

01/2018

09/2017 - 03/2018

03/2017 - 08/2017

- Achieved 81% accuracy in detecting facial key-points around eyes, nose, and mouth by developing a convolutional neural network model based on a set of architecture experiments.
- Built a facial recognition system that takes in any image containing faces and identifies the location of each face and their facial key-points using a combination of software libraries algorithms with the previous CNN model.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern at CGTIC, Universidad Autónoma de Coahuila

Saltillo. Coahuila 03/2017 - 07/2017

• Reduced more than 50% the time it takes for the 32,000+ students to perform administrative procedures by coding a multi-platform mobile application prototype that allows to do them wherever they are.

Software Developer Intern at CGV, Universidad Autónoma de Coahuila

Saltillo, Coahuila **01/2015 - 06/2015**

- Designed and re-engineered the intranet for the university's alumni program.
- Optimized 70% the registration process to the alumni program benefiting 43 higher education institutions by developing an Android app that streamlines the complementary administrative procedures.